All right so we're moving right along on our phrases and words that we used to talk about time.
好的，所以我们正在继续我们过去谈论时间的短语和单词。
I know a lot of this stuff is simple but I hope the examples helped to make it super clear for you so
我知道很多这些东西都很简单，但我希望这些例子能帮助你把它变得超级清楚，所以
that you don't have to think twice when you're using them.
使用它们时不必三思而后行。
Now let's look at back then.
现在让我们回顾一下当时的情况。
And at that time which are basically the same and we use these two phrases when we want to reference
和当时基本相同，我们要参考时使用这两个短语
a time that happened before in the past usually usually long ago Long ago.
过去发生的时间通常是很久以前很久以前。
OK.
好的。
So for example I mentioned the eighteen forties and then I say something after that about that time
例如，我提到了 18 世纪 40 年代，然后我说了一些关于那个时候的事
I would say back then is more common.
我会说当时更常见。
One thing that's important to notice and pay attention to about back then is that you've already mentioned
那时需要注意和注意的一件事是您已经提到过
the time first.
时间第一。
You can't start with back then because people will then say back when what are you talking about.
你不能从那时开始，因为人们会在你在说什么时回复。
What you have to first say the time you have to first mentioned the time or the time period and then
你要先说时间 你要先提时间或时间段 然后
and then you can use back then.
然后你可以使用回来。
And that's also how at that time is typically used although at that time can be used to talk about the
这也是当时通常使用的方式，尽管当时可以用来谈论
future and we'll do an example of that too.
未来，我们也会做一个例子。
OK so let's let's get into an example then my my great grandfather was born in nineteen oh for nineteen
好吧，让我们举个例子，然后我的曾祖父出生在十九岁哦十九岁
oh four.
哦四。
Long time ago back then.
很久以前的那个时候。
Back then comma cars were not popular.
那时逗号车并不流行。
Notice I've said when I'm talking about first I've now made a new sentence and said back then this is
请注意，当我首先谈论时，我已经说过，我现在造了一个新句子，然后说这是
usually how it's done.
通常是如何完成的。
This is not for something that happened last week.
这不适用于上周发生的事情。
It's usually years ago years ago not even months ago years ago many many years ago often.
它通常是几年前的几年前，甚至是几个月前的几年前，通常是多年前。
So we can use it to talk about our childhood for example.
所以我们可以用它来谈论我们的童年。
I grew up in the 90s.
我在90年代长大。
Back then we didn't really have the internet back then we didn't really have the internet.
那时我们还没有真正拥有互联网，那时我们还没有真正拥有互联网。
I grew up in the 90s back then.
那时我是90年代长大的。
Back then we didn't have the Internet.
那时我们还没有互联网。
Now if you're the person watching this thinking wait a second we had the internet in the 90s.
现在，如果您是观看这种想法的人，请稍等一下，我们在 90 年代就有了互联网。
OK that's true.
好的，这是真的。
But when I was a kid in the 90s it wasn't a popular thing like it is now.
但当我还是个 90 年代的孩子时，它不像现在这样流行。
Yes it's true.
对，是真的。
It was there but not many people used it.
它在那里，但没有多少人使用它。
Common people used it for everyday things to buy whatever buy stuff watch movies like we do now in the
普通人用它来购买日常用品，购买任何东西，就像我们现在在看电影一样
nineteen thirties the USA experienced tough economic times tough economic times.
十九世纪三十年代美国经历了艰难的经济时期。
All right.
好的。
At that time and we could also say back then here at that time getting a job notice I have a comma here
那时我们也可以说当时在这里收到工作通知我这里有一个逗号
getting a job was not easy.
找工作并不容易。
OK back then getting a job was not easy.
好吧，那时找工作并不容易。
All right.
好的。
So pretty simple these two back then at that time.
这两个在当时很简单。
I just want to be clear that we can use at that time in more places but I also want to be clear that
我只是想明确一点，我们当时可以在更多地方使用，但我也想明确一点
when we're talking about the past I would say back then is more common.
当我们谈论过去时，我会说当时更常见。
I feel like I hear it much more often than saying at that time but you can use at that time in the future
我觉得我听到的次数比当时说的要多，但是您将来可以在那个时候使用
for example the speaker will talk until seven thirty at that time people can ask questions.
例如演讲者会一直讲到七点三十分，那时人们可以提问。
OK.
好的。
So here at that time is about the future.
所以当时这里是关于未来的。
So it's a bit more general.
所以它更笼统一些。
It can be used in more places but that doesn't mean it's more common.
它可以在更多地方使用，但这并不意味着它更常见。
I feel like back then is much more common.
感觉那时候比较普遍。
I hear it more often.
我经常听到它。